RG 127, Connecticut Library Association
Connecticut State Library
Connecticut Library Association records
1891-1995
Connecticut State Library
Connecticut Library Association
29 cubic feet
The Connecticut Library Association (CLA) was organized in 1891 in New Haven to promote library interests by discussion and interchange of ideas and methods, and not to “trench upon the province of the American Library Association.” The original aims of the CLA have grown to include standards for librarianship, advancing types of library services, and providing opportunities for action upon mutual problems by trustees, librarians, and others interested in library affairs.
RG127
Multiple
Historical Note
The Connecticut Library Association (CLA) was organized in 1891 in New Haven to promote library interests by discussion and interchange of ideas and methods, and not to “trench upon the province of the American Library Association.” The original aims of the CLA have grown to include standards for librarianship, advancing types of library services, and providing opportunities for action upon mutual problems by trustees, librarians, and others interested in library affairs.
Scope and Content
The collection includes proceedings, scrapbooks, meeting minutes, working papers, financial records, correspondence, and publications.
Arrangement
Related Material
None.
Index Terms
Organizations:
Connecticut Library Association
Subjects:
Connecticut Library Association -- Records and correspondence; Libraries -- Connecticut; Connecticut Library Association -- History; Library science -- Societies, etc. -- Connecticut
Document Types:
Correspondence; Scrapbooks; Minutes; Publications; Financial records
Restrictions on Access
See the policy.
Container List
- Accession 1943-001, 1891-1995
  - Proceedings, 1891-1962; 5 volumes (Box 1)
    Minutes and agenda of meetings and activities.
    - Volume 1-2, 1891-1916 June 15 (Box 1)
      Labeled Volume 1-2
    - Unnumbered volume, 1916 October 26-1932 (Box 1)
    - Unnumbered volume, 1933-1939 (Box 1)
    - Unnumbered volume, 1940-1950 (Box 1)
    - Unnumbered volume, 1954-1962 (Box 1)
  - Scrapbooks, 1891-1921; 3 volumes (Box 2)
    - 1891-1899 (Box 2)
    - 1891-1921 (Box 2)
    - 1899-1920 (Box 2)
  - Attendance register, 1901 May-1940 May; 2 volumes (Box 2)
    - 1901 May-1923 October (Box 2)
    - 1924 May-1940 May (Box 2)
  - Treasurer's accounts (cash books), 1897-1948; 4 volumes (Box 2)
    - 1897-1917 June, 1 volume (Box 2)
    - 1917 September-1931 October, 1 volume (Box 2)
    - 1931 October 16-1939 October 23, 1 volume (Box 2)
    - 1939 October 25-1948 October, 1 volume (Box 2)
  - Handbook of the Connecticut Library Association, 1915-1917; 1 item (Box 2)
  - Membership list, 1916; 1 item (Box 2)
  - Correspondence and working papers, 1930-1976
    Arranged chronologically.
    - 1930-1947 (Box 3)
    - 1947-1956 (Box 4)
    - 1957-1964 (Box 5)
    - 1964-1972 (Box 6)
    - circa 1956-1976 (Box 6A)
  - Bills, 1961-1972; 9 envelopes + 2 folders (Box 7)
  - Receipts, 1961-1972; 11 items (Box 7)
  - Checks, 1962-1971; 2 envelopes (Box 7)
  - Old Savings Books, 1941-1969; 7 items (Box 7)
  - Bank statements, 1961-1969, 1971-1972; 5 envelopes + 1 folder (Box 8)
    - 1961-1969, 5 envelopes (Box 8)
    - 1971-1972, 1 folder (Box 8)
  - Check stubs, 1935-1944, 1961-1962; 5 volumes (Box 8)
    - 1935-1944, 1 volume (Box 8)
    - 1961-1962, 4 volumes (Box 8)
  - Audits, 1948, 1949, 1951, 1954, 1959-1972 (Box 8)
  - Cancelled checks, 1969-1971 (Box 8)
  - Bridgeport Regional Meeting accounts, 1971 October (Box 8)
  - Papers of the Trustees section, 1945-1962 (Box 9)
    Correspondence, by-laws, and minutes.
  - National Library Week Local Reports, 1959-1961 (Box 9)
  - College & University section, 1967-1973 (Box 9)
    Correspondence, minutes, etc.
  - Continuing Education, 1973 (Box 9)
  - Grass Roots, 1973 (Box 9)
  - Other conferences, Target '76 (Box 9A)
    Unarranged.
  - Publications, 1895-1981 (Box 10)
    - Connecticut Libraries (Box 10)
      - 1952-1954 (Box 10)
      - 1963-1964 (Box 10)
      - 1970-1973 (Box 10)
    - CLA News Bulletin, 1954 (Box 10)
    - CLA News and Views, 1954-1969 (Box 10)
    - College and University Section Newsletter, 1960 (Box 10)
    - Search, 1972-1973 (Box 10)
    - Connecticut Libraries, 1970-1979; 9 microfilm reels (Box 10A)
    - Public service announcements, 1980-1981 (Box 10A)
      - "Connecticut Libraries - They're in the Answer Business" (Box 10A)
    - Target '76, 1973-1975; 1 binder (Box 10A)
    - Target '76 patterns of service maps, 1974-1975 (Box 10A)
    - Photograph album, circa 1960-1969 (Box 10A)
    - CLA News and Views, 1966-1969; 10 issues (incomplete) (Box 10A)
    - Connecticut ribbons (Box 10B)
    - Memos and letters to membership, misc. reports, programs, etc., 1918-1964, undated (Box 10B)
    - Connecticut Yesterday and Today bibliography, 1955 June (Box 10B)
    - Strengthening and Sharing Library Resources in Connecticut, 1970, undated (Box 10B)
    - Annual Convention programs, 1896-1966 (Box 10B)
    - Articles and clippings on CLA, 1938-1974 (Box 10B)
    - Buying list of books for defense training, circa 1940 (Box 10B)
    - America's Gift to Belgium, 1922-1923 (Box 10B)
    - CLA Fiftieth Anniversary program, 1941 (Box 10B)
    - 75th Anniversary program, 1966 (Box 10B)
    - News from CLA, 1949-1950 (Box 10B)
    - Handbook of the Connecticut Library Association, 1895, 1915-1917, 1917-1921 (Box 10B)
    - Special newsletters, 1951 (Box 10B)
    - CLA bulletins, 1931-1951; 3 folders (Box 10B)
    - National Library Week, 1958; 1 envelope (Box 10B)
  - Procedures manual with revisions, 1950-1965 (Box 11)
  - Proceedings, 1966-1975 (Box 12)
    - AD HOC committees (Box 12)
    - Adult reference section, 2 folders (Box 12)
    - ALA (Box 12)
    - Annual, regionals, other meetings (Box 12)
    - Archives annual report (Box 12)
    - Budget (Box 12)
    - Cable communication (Box 12)
    - TV (Box 12)
    - Children & young people's section, 2 folders (Box 12)
    - College & university section, 2 folders (Box 12)
    - Committee on Standards (Box 12)
    - Connecticar (Box 12)
    - 84th Conference, 1975 (Box 12)
    - CLA bank statements, 1972-1973 (Box 12)
    - CLA records (Box 12)
    - CLA meeting, 1964-1966 (Box 12)
    - CLA conference, 1973 (Box 12)
    - CLA receipts & disbursements, 1972-1973 (Box 12)
    - CLA representative (Box 12)
    - Connecticut school libraries (Box 12)
    - CLA bills, 1972-1973 (Box 12)
    - Continuing education (Box 12)
    - Correspondence, 1974-1975 (Box 12)
    - Development Committee, 3 folders (Box 12)
    - Executive Board Meeting, 1975 (Box 12)
    - Minutes, 1974-1975 (Box 12)
    - Executive Board Meetings, 1966-1975 (Box 12)
    - CLA Presidents (Box 12A)
      - Denis Lorenz, 1973-1974 (Box 12A)
      - N. Lushington, 1971 Spring (Box 12A)
      - Nolan Lushington, 1970 Fall (Box 12A)
      - Evelyn Robinson, 1971 Fall (Box 12A)
      - Grace Birch, 1973 (Box 12A)
      - Marie Hurley, 1967 (Box 12A)
      - Marian Lechner, 1970 Winter (Box 12A)
    - Federal coordinator (Box 12A)
    - General statutes (Box 12A)
    - Grass Roots Committee (Box 12A)
    - Intellectual Freedom Committee, 4 folders (Box 12A)
    - Legislation (Box 12A)
    - Legislative WOR (Box 12A)
    - LTA Executive Board Minutes (Box 12A)
    - LTA (Box 12A)
    - New England Library Association, 3 folders (Box 12A)
    - Barbara Van der Lyke (Box 12A)
    - Linda Winters (Box 12A)
    - LTA section CLA (Box 12A)
    - Revisions in by-laws (Box 12A)
    - Samuel Molod (Box 12A)
    - William J. Van Beynum (Box 12A)
    - Permanent file - Mark H. Granstein - public relations (Box 12A)
    - National Library Week (Box 12A)
    - Procedures, 2 folders (Box 12A)
    - Publications, 2 folders (Box 12A)
    - Publicity (Box 12A)
    - Sec. Treasurer (Box 12A)
    - Permanent file - small libraries (Box 12A)
    - Resources & Tech services (Box 12A)
    - SCSC (Box 12A)
    - State Library Committee (Box 12A)
    - State Library Committee - choice of State Librarian (Box 12A)
    - Membership (Box 12A)
    - Technical services (Box 12A)
    - Treasurer, 2 folders (Box 12A)
    - Nancy Hiskins (Box 12A)
    - Miriam Swanson (Box 12A)
    - CLA Manual of Procedures, Constitution Bylaws, 1960; 14 copies (Box 12A)
  - Scholarship material, circa 1949-1971 (Box 13)
    Correspondence, applications, etc.
  - Newspaper clippings (Box 14)
  - Constitution & Bylaws, 1969; 2 folders (Box 14)
  - Newspapers (Box 14)
  - Permanent file - Meredith Bloss (Box 14)
  - Permanent file - Charles Funk (Box 14)
  - Permanent file - Dennis J. Weir (Box 14)
  - Permanent file - Marjorie Hernandez (Box 14)
  - Wilbur Crimmins (Box 14)
  - Mariane Woolfe (Box 14)
  - Program Committee (Box 14)
  - Permanent file - Helen E. Becker (Box 14)
  - Summary cover sheet (Box 14)
  - Special Library Association Membership, 1971 (Box 14)
  - Children & young adults (Box 14)
  - Adult services (Box 14)
  - Reports - speeches (Box 14)
  - Acquisitions (Box 14)
  - Recommended standards for public libraries of Connecticut - Library School accreditation (Box 14)
  - Catherine Mayberry (Box 14)
  - CLA News & Views (Box 14)
  - Walter Brahm (Box 14)
  - Administrative files
    - 1971-1980 (Box 15)
    - 1980-1990 (Box 16-17)
  - News and Views, 1964-1969 (Box 18)
  - Connecticut Libraries (Box 18)
    - 1970-1975 (Box 18)
    - 1979-1981 (Box 18)
    - 1982-1990 (Box 19)
  - Unprocessed records, circa 1975-1995 (Box 20)
  - Public relations material, circa 1980-1990 (Box 21)
- Accession: 1988-013C, 1948-1959
  - Files of CLA president John Crawfrod, 1948-1959 (Box 1)
- Accession: 1988-032, 1972-1974
  - CEC documentation, 1972-1974; 1 envelope (Box Envelope)
- Accession: 1990-001, 1970-1991
  - Target '76, 1970-1973 (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous records, 1978-1991 (Box 2)
- Accession: 2002-089, 1980-1983
  - Local history and genealogy subsection material, 1980-1983 (Box 1-3)
- Accession: 2002-090, 1891-1925, 1966
  - Programs and meeting notes, 1891-1899 (Box Envelope)
  - Constitution, 1891 (Box Envelope)
  - Handbooks, 1895, 1915-1917 (Box Envelope)
  - Programs, 1922, 1925 (Box Envelope)
  - 75th Anniversary letter, 1966 January 31 (Box Envelope)